Guide to the George Warren Arms Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Writings of Others, 1901-67; Series II; 0.21' (1 box)
  - [Bowers?], ----
    - "Letter from James Russell Lowell to Mary Boyle," explication, typescript, annotated, 1967 Mar (Box 6, Folder 283)
  - Cotton, ----
    - "A Letter from Charles Eliot Norton to Elizabeth Palmer Peabody," explication, typescript, corrected, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 284)
    - [Letters from Ralph Waldo Emerson to Sylvia Watson], explication, typescript, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 285)
  - Cruise, Mildred
    - "A Letter from Longfellow on a French Novel," explication, typescript, annotated, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 286)
  - Dodge, Charlyne Pond
    - "Manuscripts: A Letter by G. W. Curtis," explication, mimeograph, annotated, 1966 Mar 10 (Box 6, Folder 287)
  - Emert, ----
    - [Letter from Henry James to James Huneker], explication, mimeograph, annotated, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 288)
  - Franks, Winifred
    - "An Elizabeth Stuart Phelps Ward Letter," explication, mimeograph, annotated, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 289)
  - Hales, William
    - "Introduction to the Lathrop--Wallace Letter," typescript, annotated, 1966 Mar 10 (Box 6, Folder 290)
  - Hausberger, ---
    - "Introduction," explication of a letter from Charles Eliot Norton to Joseph P. Smith, mimeograph, 1967 Mar (Box 6, Folder 291)
  - Howells, William Dean
    - Draft fragment, "Literary Friends and Acquaintance," autobiography, typescript and holograph, corrected (Box 6, Folder 292)
  - Hurley, M.
    - [Letter from Oliver Wendell Holmes to Benjamin Robbins Curtis, explication, mimeograph, corrected (Box 6, Folder 293)
  - Jenkins, Billie L.
    - "A Letter by Oliver Wendell Holmes Written in 1879," explication, mimeograph, annotated, 1965 Mar 9 (Box 6, Folder 294)
  - Lee, Jae Num
    - "Introduction to the Letter from James Russell Lowell to George William Curtis," typescript, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 295)
  - [Lundquist?], ----
    - "Letter from C. P. Cranch to Dr. O. W. Holmes," explication, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 296)
  - McHenry, ----
    - Drafts, "Field's Letter to W. L. Stone," explication, mimeograph, annotated, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 297)
  - Mencken, H. L. (Henry Louis)
    - "James Huneker," biography, printed version, The Evening Sun, 1921 Feb 14 (Box 6, Folder 298)
  - Morris, Jesse
    - "A Letter from Edgar J. Fawcett to Mary Louise Booth," explication, mimeograph, annotated, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 299)
  - Mourol, Mary F. de
    - "Introduction," explication of letters from Mary Eleanor Wilkins to "Mr. Knight," mimeograph, annotated, 1965 Mar 9 (Box 6, Folder 300)
  - Norton, Charles Eliot
    - "The New Life by Dante," translation, typescript, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 301)
    - "The Story of Assos," letter, typescript carbon, corrected, 1901 Apr 15 (Box 6, Folder 302)
  - Phillips, ----
    - "Introduction," explication of a letter from Horace Elisha Scudder to Dewitt Miller, typescript, corrected, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 303)
  - Sethi, ----
    - "A Lowell Letter," explication, mimeograph, annotated, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 304)
  - Stege, John
    - "Two Letters by H. E. Scudder," explication, mimeograph, annotated, 1965 Mar 9 (Box 6, Folder 305)
  - Watson, Alan
    - [Letter from Everet Augustus Duyckinck], explication, mimeograph, annotated, 1965 Mar 9 (Box 6, Folder 306)
  - Webb, Judy
    - "Introduction and Annotations to a Letter from Donald G. Mitchell...," mimeograph, annotated (Box 6, Folder 307)
  - Unidentified
    - "Charles Eliot Norton, 1827-1908," mimeograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 308)
    - "James Gibbons Huneker (1857-1921)," mimeograph, corrected, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 309)
- Subject Files, 1962-85; Series III; 0.21' (1 box)
  Series III, Subject Files, is arranged alphabetically by name.
  - Alcott, Amos Bronson, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 310)
  - Black, William, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 311)
  - Bonet-Maury, ----, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 312)
    Includes copy of letter from [Schiellery?]
  - Brooks, Charles T., n.d. (Box 7, Folder 313)
  - Carnegie, Andrew, 1977, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 314)
  - Channing, William Emery, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 315)
  - Crawford, F. Marion (Francis Marion), n.d. (Box 7, Folder 316)
  - Fawcett, Edgard, 1962-79, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 317)
  - Hale, Edward Everett, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 318)
  - Holmes, Oliver Wendell, 1972-78, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 319)
    Includes copy of letter from Holmes
  - Howe, Julia Ward, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 320)
  - Howells, William Dean, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 321)
    Includes copies of letters from Howells to Stuart Sterne
  - James, Henry, 1970-76, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 322)
  - Judd, Sylvester, 1977 Oct (Box 7, Folder 323)
  - Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 324)
    Includes copy of letter from Longfellow
  - Parton, James, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 325)
  - Pound, Dorothy, 1973 Dec 11 (Box 7, Folder 326)
  - Stoddard, Charles Warren, 1972 Nov (Box 7, Folder 327)
  - Tourgée, Albion Winegar, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 328)
  - Twain, Mark, 1985 Jul (Box 7, Folder 329)
  - Ward, Artemus, 1972 Nov (Box 7, Folder 330)
  - Wendell, Barrett (Box 7, Folder 331)
  - Others, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 332)
- Restricted Fragile, 0.21' (1 box)
  Box 8, Restricted Fragile, contains fragile originals. The material is arranged in folder order and may be seen only with permission of the appropriate curator. Preservation photocopies have been substituted in the main files for reference use.
  Conditions Governing Access
  Box 8: Restricted fragile material. Reference surrogates have been substituted in the main files. For further information consult the appropriate curator.
  - Box 5, folder 237 (Box 8, Folder 333)
  - Box 6, folder 299 (Box 8, Folder 334)